On the one hand, there should be a free health insurance provided by the government. On the
other hand, there should be another health insurance policy that covers the entire family even if it is
50 lakhs or 60 lakhs in case of major illnesses. That
too should
be within 400-500 per month. Is there
any idea for that?
Praveen is now becoming aware of personal finance issues and a
10 lakh policy is
not enough for his family these days. He now wants to have a health insurance policy of at least not less than one crore
rupees.
But since the premium is
more than ₹50000 per year, he is
thinking about it. Here you may have two doubts.
One is that if a ₹5 lakh
health insurance policy
costs ₹17000 per year, then a ₹95 lakh health
insurance policy costs just
₹6000 per year. So now what
Karthik wants is that the
policy given by the company should not be a waste. At the same time,
another health
insurance policy should come with a lower premium for the entire family. In
this health insurance policy
This is a great policy
because he already has
10 lakhs covered by Aarogyasri,
so after using Aarogyasri,
this policy will
be used only if the amount exceeds ₹10 lakh. To take a
health insurance policy of one crore rupees for the entire family, he
must
be a millionaire, is it not possible for us?
said
a man named Ravi, who
came from a village and is doing a small job in a company in Hyderabad.
He belongs to a small
farmer family, so his family has
Aarogyasri, which is provided by the government.
At that time, its insurance cover was up
to 5 lakhs, now it seems to be up to 10 lakhs.
After watching various videos related to health insurance,
Ravi got a fear that these
days the cost of treatments like cancer, kidney
transplantation, heart surgery and the like can
be 20 lakhs to 50 lakhs.
Since the limit of Aarogyasri is low,
now if we want to take another health insurance policy for the entire family, it will
cost 40000 to 60000 per year.
He can afford the premium from 4000 to 6000 per year
but he cannot afford this amount. On the
one hand, there should be
Arogyasri which is given free by the government. On the other hand, there should be
another health insurance policy that covers the entire family even if it is 50 lakhs or 60 lakhs in case of major illnesses.
That too should be within 400-500 per month. Is there
any idea for that? Ravi's
matter aside, now
another problem of a person named Karthik is that he is
working in a multinational company.
His company is already
giving him a health insurance policy that covers his entire family.
Its limit is only up to ₹5 lakh.
Karthik is planning to have a health insurance policy of
at least one crore rupees to cover his entire family. If I
check online, the
premium is almost up
to 50000 per year. Now his problem is
whether it should be adjusted with the health insurance given by the company or
else he will have to pay a premium of 50000 and go to a health insurance company
outside.  He has been thinking about whether to
take an insurance policy for the last six months.
So now Karthik
wants that the policy given by the company should
not be a waste. At the same time, he should get a
different health insurance policy for the entire family
with a lower premium.
Leaving aside Ravi and Karthik's issue, Praveen has
another problem. He took a health insurance policy of
10 lakhs when he joined a new job five years ago.
Now he is married and
has children. The family has only a family
floater policy of 10 lakhs. As
Praveen is now becoming more aware of personal finance matters, a
10 lakh policy is not enough for his family these days.
At least not less than one crore rupees. He
now wants to have a health insurance policy.
But since the premium is more than 50,000 per year, he is thinking about it
because the health
insurance premium
increases every year, so he is
afraid that in the future he will have to pay premiums in lakhs.
Ravi Karthik and Praveen are afraid that what these three should
do now? They should follow Suresh and
Suresh.  Now let's see what this
guy named Suresh did. He is a junior in my college.
He has a family floater health policy. It has a
coverage of only ₹5 lakh.
For this, he is paying a premium of ₹17 thousand per year.
After watching our video, I got an idea that Suresh should also have a health insurance policy of at least ₹1 crore.
One day, he called me and
said that if he wants to take a health insurance policy of ₹1 crore for the entire family, he must definitely have a court issue. It is not possible for us.
Then I asked him one thing. Can he
pay ₹6000 per year?
He took the policy on the same day. Suresh is
30 years old, his wife is 30 years old, his
son is 10 years old, and his
daughter is five years old. The premium to be paid for this family is
₹95 lakh. That
is, just
₹6000 per year. Here
you may have two doubts. One is
that if you
pay ₹17000 per year for a health insurance policy of ₹5 lakh, then you will get ₹95
lakh health insurance.  Even if the insurance policy is
just ₹6000 per year, it is the same. The
second doubt is why the number ₹95 lakhs is
because he
already has a policy of ₹5 lakhs. So
what is the health insurance policy that he has taken so far? It is a top-up health insurance policy. It can be
said that this is an excellent policy in health
insurance policy. Now let
's know in detail what is a top-up health insurance
policy. What happens in a top-up health insurance policy is that
your health
insurance policy accepts that claim only after a particular amount is crossed.
Suppose you have invested that particular amount of ₹5 lakhs.
This policy pays money only for claims made after ₹5 lakhs.
Suppose you have invested that particular amount of ₹10 lakhs. Then
this policy pays money only after ₹10 lakhs is crossed.
Here, the ₹5
lakhs or ₹10 lakhs that we have mentioned are
called by one name.
What is the deductible in this policy? For example, Ravi has a
Arogyasri policy of up
to 10 lakhs. How does he take a top-up policy? That is, if there is a
claim exceeding 10 lakhs, that policy will be
required only. That is, if there is a deductible of ₹10 lakhs, that is, if
he
wants a policy of one crore rupees, he will
take a policy of only 90 lakh rupees
because he already has
10 lakhs covered by Arogyasri.
Therefore, after using Arogyasri,
this policy will
be used only if it exceeds 10 lakhs. Now, if Karthik is taken into consideration, the
company already gives him a health policy of ₹5 lakhs.
How does he take a top-up policy? That is, if there is a claim exceeding ₹5 lakhs,
that
policy will be required only. That is, if there is a deductible of ₹5 lakhs, that is, if
he
wants a policy of one crore rupees, he will
take a policy of only 90 lakh rupees
because he already has a
health insurance policy of five lakhs given by his company.
Therefore, after using it,
this policy will be used only if it exceeds ₹5 lakhs.  The policy is
used. Now, if we take the case of Praveen,
he has already taken a
family floater policy of ₹10 lakhs from a health insurance company.
How does he take this top-up policy? That is, if there is
any claim beyond
₹10 lakhs, the policy will be overdrawn. That is, ₹10 lakhs is
deductible here. Suppose he wants a
policy of one crore rupees now.
He takes only a ₹90 lakh policy
because he already has a ₹10 lakh health
policy. So, the
top-up policy that he is going to take now can be
taken from the company he already has
or from a different company. It is
not necessary that the two health policies be from the same company. If you want to understand why the premium of these top-up policies
is so low,
you should first know how these top-up policies actually work. Let's
first look at Scenario One. You have a
basic health insurance
policy of ₹5 lakhs. In addition, you also have another policy, a
top-up health insurance policy of ₹95 lakhs,
in which ₹5 lakhs
is the deductible amount.  For treatment in the hospital,
you want to claim ₹4 lakh,
then your top-up policy will
not pay you any amount.
You will get that claim amount from the policy you took first.
Now let's
look at Scenario 2. In the same situation as
mentioned earlier, you want to claim ₹6 lakh.
Then you will get ₹5
lakh from the first policy and the remaining ₹1 lakh
from the top-up policy.
Now in the same year,
you want to claim ₹3 lakh again,
it will not be paid from the top-up policy
because here the deductible
is ₹5 lakh. What you
need to understand here is that
any claim you make every year should be
more than the deductible amount. As
we mentioned earlier,
why does my friend Suresh pay only ₹6000 premium per year for a ₹95 lakh top-up family floater health policy? This means that the
risk is low for the health insurance company
because there is no payment to be made up to the deductible amount.  There is
no work, so
the number of claims they receive
is less and the claim amount is also
less. The liability
of the company that gives the top-up health policy is also much less than the first company.
Now the real question is where to get this top-up
policy. One is
directly through an agent you know, if he
has knowledge about health insurance.
Another thing is that
even the agent does not suggest such policies, i.e. top-up policies,
because the commission in this is
almost zero. If you do not want to go to the agent, you can
get it online. There
are two platforms for that, Policy Bazaar
and Dito. We are giving the links of both in the description below the video.
However, this is
not a promotional video. Health
insurance is a big boring
subject. Even if you
have watched this video patiently till now, like this
video and leave a comment
because the information given in this video is
not complete information. You should
also know about another policy, its name is Super
Top-up Health Insurance Policy. If more
people like and comment on it, then
another detailed video about it will be made.
Let's be rich and stay rich.